MELISSA GARZA

Austin, TX melissa.garza@utexas.edu linkedin.com/in/melissagarza

Front-End Developer

- SUMMARY -

Front-End Developer with 6+ years work experience. Experienced in revamping existing customer websites with a priority on customer satisfaction. Responsible for greatly decreasing bottlenecks in software development life cycle by establishing Git workflows and code reviews. Oversaw the continuous integration and deployment of software releases, while also developing enhancements and fixing issues on client websites.

- SKILLS —

JavaScript, HTML, CSS / SCSS, jQuery, Git / Mercurial, Backbone, Underscore, Handlebars, Node, Bootstrap / Foundation, Gulp / Grunt

EXPERIENCE

Oracle NetSuite

Senior Web Developer

Jan 2017 - Feb 2020

- · Continuously integrated and deployed enhancements and fixes to both product and customer website customizations.
- Responsible for upgrading and maintaining the Campus Stores bundle, a product that provides e-commerce solutions to multiple clients. Converted and refactored pre-existing code to use a new API, increasing efficiency in continuous delivery to clients.
- Spearheaded the effort to establish Git workflows for each channel on the team, to decrease issues occurring in the continuous
 integration pipeline. Administered the Git repositories for each channel and used Git to establish and participate in code reviews
 as well as keeping better track of releases.
- Held training sessions for other members of the team to learn Git and the established Git workflows for their channel. Made available to answer any Git questions.
- Mentored a new hire during the upgrade process of our product by pair-programming and answering any questions they had throughout the process.
- Practiced Agile methodologies using JIRA and Git to deliver timely releases of the Campus Stores bundle.

Associate Web Developer

Apr 2016 - Jan 2017

- Trained in SuiteCommerce Advanced (SCA) development as well as in NetSuite ERP administration and SuiteScript.
- Worked with clients to develop customizations for their e-commerce websites using NetSuite's SCA web store framework.
- Participated in meetings with clients to assist in asking and answering questions to document requirements for future development.
- Experience with resolving issue tickets in the NetSuite system.

ZeitCode

Junior Front-End Developer

Oct 2012 - Oct 2014

- Began as an intern and advanced in web development. Progressed to have a more solid understanding of different languages and technologies to later apply them to a wide variety of projects.
- Self-taught WordPress to build a website with provided mockups and designs (http://angelsintheaisle.com).
- · Learned the Django framework to use with Python to work on different websites for different clients.

- EDUCATION -

The University of Texas at Austin

2007 - 2011

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

• Participated in group activities with the Electronic Game Developers Society through college.